Fullstack and Mobile Developer with 3+ years of experience in writing quality code for mobile apps and web applications. Efficient with Agile development methodology and proficient in building optimized applications, planning, leading a team and collaborative development.

EMAIL: amarjeet.sarma3641@gmail.com

FIND ME ONLINE: GitHub; LinkedIn

EXPERIENCE

Career Leap

TECHNICAL LEAD - Full Time, Nov 2021 - June 2022

- Major responsibilities include working on planning of proper scalable architectures, maintaining the existing codebase, handling sensitive deployments and operations, and leading the tech team.
- Built free community tools for value creation from scratch with the team. like:
 - TwittrGems
 - Got ranked ProductHunt #1 Product of the day within 24 hours after release.
 - Got nominated for **ProductHunt Golden Kitty** Awards 2021.
 - Got featured in multiple videos and articles.
 - Upskill India
 - Achieved a **DAU of 20+** with 1k+ downloads and 4.9 stars on play store.
 - CoffeeHours
 - Helped 200+ college students get free career consultancy and mentorship for free.

Brand Warikoo

SDE - Freelance, MAR 2022 - Present

• Working with Ankur Warikoo himself in building an application ecosystem for providing a seamless learning experience for everyone.

Rivi, Bangalore

SDE Consultant - Freelance, Nov 2021 - Present

• Major responsibilities include working on planning, taking major tech decisions and guiding the tech team.

SDE 2 - Full Time, Jun 2020 - Nov 2021

SDE 1 - Full Time, Aug 2020 - Jun 2021

- Worked with the team on some major features native android app of Rivi for the users, having a 4.5+ stars play store rating.
- Worked as a part of Rivi labs, worked on a few Frontend and React Native apps for clients.

MyBliss

REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER - Freelance, JUN 2021 - Present

- Worked on multiple apps including MyBliss and JoyFull Eastie.
- Working on an ongoing project for **AIMI** in correspondence with Dalai Lama Foundation and a parking reservation system for **GoStateParks**.

Decathlon

ANDROID ENGINEER - Freelance, JUN 2021 - MAR 2022

• Worked on major features of Decathlon's AllForSport app.

ZLab Global

BACKEND DEVELOPER - Freelance, SEPT 2021 - APR 2022

TheNewBoston (Open-source)

CORE TEAM FRONTEND DEVELOPER - Part Time, NOV 2020 - APR 2021

SKILLS 🌼

Languages: Kotlin, Typescript, JavaScript, Java, Python, C, C++.

Tools I've worked with in the past:

Mobile:

- Java and Kotlin.
- MVVM, MVC, Clean Architecture.
- Dependency Injection.
- JUint and Espresso.
- React Native for cross platform apps.
- Kotlin Multiplatform Mobile.

Fullstack:

- React, NextJS.
- Redux, redux-toolkit.
- Jest, react-testing-library.
- NodeJS for Monoliths and Microservices.
- Docker.
- Kubernetes.
- Github Actions, CircleCI

Common:

- MongoDB, MySql, Firebase, SQL, GraphQL
- Git

EDUCATION

Tezpur University — BTech, ECE - 2016 - 2020